Guide to the Howard S. Liddell papers, 1920-1967
Liddell, Howard S. papers, 1920-1967
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Howard S. Liddell papers, 1920-1967
14-23-1466
Howard S. Liddell, 1895-1962
15 cubic ft., 1 tape recording
Correspondence, lecture and research notes, course materials, financial and subject files, manuscripts, printed materials, photographs, diagrams, glass slides and negatives, movie film, tape recording.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Personal and professional papers and materials of Cornell University professor of psychobiology, founder of the Behavior Farm Laboratory.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Howard Scott Liddell, 1895-1962, was professor of psychology and psychobiology and founded and directed the Behavior Farm Laboratory at Cornell University. Following Liddell's death, the lab was renamed the Liddell Laboratory of Comparative and Physiological Psychology.
CHRONOLOGY
1917 Graduated Univ. of Michigan
1918 MA
1923 Cornell Univ. Ph.D.
1919 Cornell Univ. Instructor
1926 Cornell Univ. Assistant Prof.
1930 Cornell Univ. Chairman of Dept. of Physiology in the Medical College
1939 Cornell Univ. Prof. of Psychology
1947 Cornell Univ. Prof. of Psychobiology
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Personal papers include school notebooks, 1920's, and miscellany. Professional papers include correspondence, acknowledgements, recommendations for students, Department of Psychology and Behavior Farm Laboratory correspondence; conference and lecture notes, manuscripts, programs, and memos, 1952-1963; student notes, rollbooks, and course materials; research notebooks and files, ca. 1930-1959; Department of Psychology financial files, 1926-1963, and subject files on topics including the Behavior Farm, equipment, and procedures; manuscripts and printed materials include reprints by Liddell and other authors; also visual materials such as photograph albums, diagrams, glass slides and negatives, and movie film dealing with pig, sheep, dog, and goat experiments at the Behavior Farm. Correspondents include the American Russian Institute, American Society for Research in Psychosomatic Problems, Association for Advancement of Psychoanalysis, W. Horsley Gantt, A. U. Moore, Leon J. Saul, J. Paul Scott, graduate students, publishers, and other scientists and psychologists.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Liddell, H. S. (Howard Scott), 1895-; Scott, John Paul, 1909-; Gantt, W. Horsley (William Horsley), 1892-; Saul, Leon Joseph, 1901-; Moore, A. U.; Cornell University--Faculty; Cornell University--Students; American Russian Institute; American Society for Research in Psychosomatic Problems; Association for the Advancement of Psychoanalysis
Subjects:
Psychology--Research; Psychology--Study and teaching
Form and Genre Terms:
Motion pictures
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Personal
Box 1
Series II. Correspondence
Boxes 1-2
Series III. Professional Papers
Box 3
Conferences
Lectures
Students' Notes
Series IV. Research Papers
Boxes 3-5
Notebooks
Notes and Files
Research Files
Series V. Cornell Dept. Files
Boxes 5-7
Manuscripts
Financial
Subject Files
Series VI. Printed Material
Boxes 7-9
Series VII. Visual Material
Boxes 10-20
Photographs
Diagrams
Glass Slides and Negatives
Movie Films
Series XIII. Miscellaneous
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Personal
  - Notebook: Prof. Simpson's lectures on the Endocrine Organs, March 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exam Book: Notes on Endocrine Organs (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notebook: Prof. Simpson's lectures, March 1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Notebook: Physiology of Nervous System, Vol. 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Liddell Notebook: Series 1922, Learning Tests (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Notebook: Organic Chemistry (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Notebooks: Physiology (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
  - Notebook: Physiology notes, nervous system (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Notebook (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Liddell accomplishments (list format) and biography (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Liddell - W.H.O. (Speech?), 1954 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Liddell Memorial Address by F. S. Freeman, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - History and Prospects of the Behavior Farm Laboratory at Cornell, by Howard Liddell (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - A (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Acknowledgements - of Monograph (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Acknowledgements - Neurosis articles (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Acknowledgements - Pavlov papers (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Acknowledgements - Veterinary papers (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Acknowledgements and Invitations (Box 1, Folder 22-23)
  - Altmann, M. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - A - Altmann, Arbitmann, Amstey (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - American Russian Institute (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - American Society for Research in Psychosomatic Problems (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - American Society for Research in Psychosomatic Problems - Cttees. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Anderson (Box 1, Folder 29-30)
  - Anderson - Parmenter monograph (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Annual Review of Physiology (T. M. Luck - editor) (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - B (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Beach (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bentley (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Bitterman (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Blauvelt, Helen (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Block, James D. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Boring, Edwin Garry (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - C (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Cinema Register (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Cornell University (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Cortin (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - D (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - President Day (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Dean's Office (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Dunbar (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Dworkin (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - E (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - F (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Farm Business (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Finger (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Frank, L. K. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Fremont - Smith, Frank (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Fulton - re. Chapter (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - G (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Gantt, W. Horsley (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Graduate School (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Graduate Students (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Gregg (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - H (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Hartman, F. A. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Humphrey, George (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Hunt (Chapter) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - I (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - J (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Jackson, Roscoe B. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - James, W. T. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Jensen, Arthur V. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Job applications and inquiries (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - K (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Kardiner (Assoc. for Research in Psychoanalysis & Exp. Psychodynamics) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Kennard, Margaret A. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Kepler, Edwin J. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Korea (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Kubie - N.Y. Psychoanalytic Institute (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - L (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Library (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Little (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - M (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Marcuse (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Markel Foundation (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Masserman (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Mead, Margaret (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Miles, Walter (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Monograph (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Moore, A. U. - General (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - N (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - O (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - P (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Physiological Review (Gerard) (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Problems of Neurotic Behavior - Cttee., 1937-38 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Psychosomatic Medicine (Business Corresp. & Minutes) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Psychosomatic Medicine (about Manuscripts) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Public Relations (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Publishing (Box 2, Folder 36-39)
  - R (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Recommendations - Medical School (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Recommendations (Box 2, Folder 42-43)
  - Richter (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Rogalsky, G. F. (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - S (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Sabine, George H. (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Saul, Leon J. (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Scott, J. Paul (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Selinsky - Assoc. for Adv. of Psychoanalysis (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Sutherland, George F. (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - T (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - U (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Van Cleef Library (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Veterans Education (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - W (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - John Wiley and Sons (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Y-Z (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Unanswered Letters ("Fan Mail") (Box 2, Folder 59-60)
- Series III. Professional Papers
  - Conferences
    - "Self-Control under Stressful Situations" (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Macy Foundation Conference, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Macy Foundation Conference - correspondence (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Ross Conference, Sept. 1962 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Animal Medical Center Ded., 1962 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - American Museum of Natural History (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Hixon Symposium (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Conf. Correspondence, 1952-54 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - World Health Organization 2nd Conf., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Conf. Correspondence, 1955-59 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Conf. Correspondence, 1960-63 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Conferences - Programs (Box 3, Folder 12-14)
  - Lectures
    - Psychoanalytic Colloquium (notes) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Speaking Engagements (corresp.) (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Psychology 440 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Neurotic Behavior in Animals and Man (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Student Notes
    - Problems in Social Medicine, Gertrude Hanchett, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Psychology 133 Term Report, Alan M. Levy, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Psychology lee, Jane Ruggles, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Physiological Stress and the Gen. Adoption Syndrome, H. D. Arbitman, ca. 1949 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Response to Stress of Modified early Development, M. Amstey, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Students, grades, registration cards (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Lists (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Pocket Notebooks (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Roll Books (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Courses (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Behavior Farm, Lab. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Corresp. concerning students (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Series IV. Research Papers
  - Notebooks
    - Notebooks (Box 3, Folder 31-43)
    - Notebooks (Box 4, Folder 1-8)
  - Notes and Files
    - Conditioned Reflex Notes, [ca. 1930] (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Report of Progress in C. R. Studies, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - "The Hypnosis of Animals" by H. Dexter, Translated by H. Schulman and M. Stern, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Pavlov - Miscellaneous, [ca. 1934] (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - External Inhibition or Negative Induction in the Cerebral Cortex, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Observations on Experimental Neurosis in Sheep, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Effect of Cortin on Experimental Neurosis in Sheep, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Abstracts, [1935-39] (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - New Approach to Problem of Experimental Neurosis, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Environment of the Experimental Neurosis, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Nervous Strain in Domesticated Animals and in Man, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - A Breathing Mark for Animals of Medium Size, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - EEG's and their Interpretation/Interpretation of Electrical Activity in the Brain, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Bentley - Lectures to Medical Classes, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Effect of Cortin in Glycerine Orally Administered on the Experimental Neurosis in Sheep, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Experimental Neurosis in the Pig - Quin F. Curtis, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Preliminary Comment on Investigation of Patterns of Activity, [1937] (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous, [1937-41] (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Parmenter - Dissociation Report, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Project for Committee on Problems of Neurotic Behavior, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Goldman Thesis: "Experimental Investigation of Behavior of Goat by Conditioned Reflex Method," 1939 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Direct Current Potentials Associated with Human Ovulation, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Freud Seminar, [1939-40] (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Parmenter - D. C. Potentials Associated with Ovulation and Fatigue, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Goat Paper - Altmann and Goldmann, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Role of Animal Experimentation in Psychiatry As Illustrated by Experimental Neurosis, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - W. T. James - Transfer of Conditioned Avoiding Reaction/Significance of Work on CMR, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - [The Conditioned Reflex Experiment - Pony as Subject] with photos, ca. 1940 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - M. Altmann - Translations, [1940-41] (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - W. T. James - Report on Nutrition in Dogs, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Marcuse and Moore - Heart Rate and Respiration Preceding and Following Audiogenic Seizures in White Rat, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - M. Altmann, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Chapter 9 - Comparative Psychology, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Altmann Diary/Sutherland: Pigs #2, 5, 7, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Psychoanalytic Colloquium, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Experimental Approach to Psychoanalytic Concepts, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Hunt Handbook Chapter: Conditioned Reflex Method and Experimental Neurosis, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Voodoo Death, [1942] (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Animal Behavior Studies Bearing on the Problem of Pain, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Abstract - Marcuse and Moore, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Chapter 27 - Conditioned Reflex, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Harvey - Goat #7, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - MSS in Progress, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Experimental Neurosis, [ca. 1944] (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - [Student Resumes, Biographies], 1940's (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Research Files
    - [Research Experiment Livestock], 1956-59 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Behavior Farm Research - Nick's Case (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Goat #13 (Snowflake T3) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Watsonian Behaviorism (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Equipment (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - References - Experimental Production of Behavior Derangement (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Important Developments in Am. Soc. Psych. in Past Decade (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Lindemann and Finesinger: "Response of Psychoneurotics to Adrenalin and Mecholyl" (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - S. Cobb Bibliography (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Preface (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Morphological Form and its Relation to Reflex Action and Behavior (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Early MSS (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Effect of Bromides (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Conditioned Salivary Reflex and its Inhibition (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Physiological Psychology (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Series V. Cornell Dept. Files
  - Manuscripts
    - Altmann (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Altmann on Hediger (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Bentley (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Besharat (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Blauvelt (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Block (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Block, Moore (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Brunner (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Cottrell (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Delamater (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Deutsch (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Gantt (Box 5, Folder 27-28)
    - Grau (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Hersher, Richmond, Moore (Box 5, Folder 30-33)
    - Liddell (Box 5, Folder 34-54)
    - Liddlee, McCay (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Liddell, Minami (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Lubow (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Lubow, Moore (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Lyman (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Massermann (Box 5, Folder 60-61)
    - Miller (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Minami, Moore, Liddell (Box 5, Folder 63-64)
    - Mirsky, Miller, Stein (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Moore (Box 5, Folder 66-78)
    - Moore, Amstey (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
    - Mowrer (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Newton, Bovard (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Papez (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Resnick, Krus, Raskin, Rivera, Freeman (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Romagnoli (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Samuels (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Scott (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
    - Shands (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Whitehorn (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
    - "Anxiety and Pleasure" (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Audiogenic Seizures - Colloquium, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - "Effect of Post-Partum Separation of Mother and Kid on Maternal Care in the Domestic Goat" (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - "Efficiency and Fatigue" (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Experiments - Not Ours (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Experiments - Ours (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Laboratory - MSS, Projects (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Maternal - Neonate Experiment, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Newsletters (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - "Response to Stress" (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - "Sympathicotonia" (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - [Tiny, Ben (pigs)] (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous MSS (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Financial
    - Estimates, [1926-34] (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Various Estimates: Budgets, Grants, [1926-37] (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Budget Material, [1930-44] (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Heckscher Fund, [1931-38] (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Sackett & Sage Funds, [1931-38] (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Monthly Expenditures - Behavior Farm, [1931-44] (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Rockefeller Grant, 1935-36 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Field Station: Improvement Plans - Estimates, [1935-39] (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - RE Equipment (Rockefeller Grant), [1936-37] (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Rockefeller Grant, 1936-37 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Rockefeller Grant, 1937-38 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Lamkin Farm - Rentals, [1937-44] (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Macy Grant, 1937-41 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Physiological Field Station, [1938-40] (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Rockefeller Grant, 1938-40 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Financial Estimates - Budgets, [1939-44] (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Balance Sheets [Letters, Bills], 1939-59 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Rockefeller Grant, 1940-41 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Expense Sheets, [1940-47] (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Rockefeller Grant, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Behavior Farm Expenses, 1944-47 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Accounts, 1947-51 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Accounts, [1948-55] (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Accounts, [1951-54] (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Accounts, [1954-61] (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - USPH Correspondence, 1947-60 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Travel - expenses, vouchers, [1949-54] (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - USPH Grant: Corresp. on Budget, [1950-52] (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Payroll, 1950-51 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Payroll/Personnel/Travel, [1950-54] (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Requisitions, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - [Vouchers], 1951-53 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - New York Hospital, [1952-53] (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Feed, 1952-54 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - USPH, [1952-55] (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - [Various Orders], 1953-54 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - [Cornell Requisitions], 1953-56 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Block - Requisitions, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - [Research Grant Application and Material], 1955-63 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Macy, [1957-62] (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - [H.E.W. Research Grant Application], 1960 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Grant Application, [1960-63] (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Subject
    - Animals - Info. Procedures, [1941-46] (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Letters of Recommendation (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Papers in Progress (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Dept. Minutes, 1960-63 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Scientific Meetings, 1940-44 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Courses - Exams, Outlines, Etc. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Curriculum (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Autopsies on Experimental Animals - Behavior Farm Lab (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Blauvelt (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Wiring Diagrams for Procedure Circuits (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Macy Conference, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Endowment Proposal, [1936-37] (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Animals - Registry (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - General Committee Division of Biology (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Farm Land - Correspondence, Etc. (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Cornell U. Medical College (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Lab Business (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Department Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 35)
- VI. Printed Material
  - "Emotional Hazards in Animals and Man" by H. Liddell (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Reprints by Liddell (Box 7, Folder 37-40)
  - Page Proof (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Reprints about Liddell (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Magazines about Liddell (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Psychophysiology Newsletters (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Reprints - James D. Block (Box 7, Folder 45-46)
  - Reprints - John L. Fuller (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Reprints - report by World Health Organization (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Reprints - Salpeter, Lyman, Block, Koella, Samuels, Tobach, Bowlby, Goldfarb (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Reprints - Mother-Neonate Interaction (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Monographs - Psychosomatic Medicine (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Reprints by other authors (Box 8, Folder 4-7)
  - Clippings (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Conferences, (3" legal box) (Box 9)
    - Macy Foundation Conference, 1960 (Box 9)
- VII. Visual Material
  - Photographs
    - 3 albums (mostly pig shock experiments) (Box 10)
    - Prof. Liddell with sheep and unidentified man, ca. 1962 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Goat & sheep shock graphs (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Goat & sheep shock experiments (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Photos used in Effect of LSD-25 - on the walking activity & pattern in the goat (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Kate furious on shock day (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Negatives (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Diagrams
    - Experiments on palatability of good constituents - with photos & graphs - by W. T. James (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Figures for Respiratory "Fingerprint" of Nervous States - Sutherland, Wolf, and Kennedy, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
    - Records of Metabolic Rate Determination, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Glass Slides and Negatives
    - Pig - also contains set of slides of cat experiments labeled from University of Chicago (Box 11)
    - Dog (Box 12)
    - Slides of apparatus and goats and sheep experiments (Box 13)
    - Slides of apparatus and experimental results, ca. 1920-30 (Box 14)
    - Sheep and apparatus, ca. 1928 (Box 15)
    - Experimental results, ca. 1938-47, Note: torn emulsion on negative in slot #28 (Box 16)
  - Movie Films
    - Movie Film, 218 reels (Box 17-20)
- VIII. Miscellaneous
  - Tape recording, tr. 3916
  - Phonograph album, R-8